A Guide to the Virginia Academy of Science Records, 1920-2005
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
- Box 32, Boyd Harshbarger Papers, 1957-1969 (Box 32)
  - VAS Research Committee, 1962-1963
  - Finance Committee, 1962-1963
  - Long Range Planning Commission, 1962-1963
  - Local Arrangements Committee, 1963
  - VAS Council Meeting, March 24, 1963
  - VAS--S. S. Obenshain, 1963-1964
  - Research Committee, 1963-1964
  - Finance Committee, 1964
  - Research Committee, 1964
  - Finance Committee, 1964-1965
  - VAS President--S. S. Obenshain, 1964-1965
  - Council Meetings, 1964-1965
  - VAS Executive Secretary--Berry Rodney, 1964-1965
  - VAS officers, 1964-1965
  - Long Range Planning Committee, 1964-1969
  - Research Committee, 1965
  - VAS Annual Meeting, May 6-8, 1965
  - Papers submitted for Horsley Award, 1965
  - VAS Council Meetings, 1965-1966
  - Finance Committee, 1965-1966
  - Finance Committee Meeting, 1966
  - VAS Miscellaneous, 1966
  - VAS Council Members, 1966-1967
  - Virginia Journal of Science--Dr. Herbert McKennis, 1966-1968
  - Council Meeting, 1967
  - VAS Miscellaneous, 1967
  - VAS Executive Secretary-Treasurer--Berry Rodney, 1967
  - Finance Committee Meeting, 1967
  - Publications Committee, 1967
  - Fund Raising Committee, 1967-1969
  - VAS Visiting Lectures, 1968
  - VAS Miscellaneous, 1968-1969
  - Advanced Seminar in Statistics--National Science Foundation (2 folders), 1969
- Box 33, Boyd Harshbarger Papers, 1969-1984, n.d. (Box 33)
  - Advanced Seminar in Statistics--National Science Foundation (2 folders), 1969
  - NATO European Trip (2 folders), 1969
  - Miscellaneous documents of the VAS Annual Meeting, 1983
  - Miscellaneous documents of the VAS Annual Meeting, 1984
  - Miscellaneous brochures and papers, n.d.
- Box 34, Edgar V. Russell Papers, 1941-1971, n.d. (Box 34)
  - VPI Science Club--Miscellaneous, 1941-1971
  - Virginia Talent Search Files, 1949-1950
  - Virginia Junior Talent Search Certificates, 1953
  - Virginia Science Talent Search Reports, 1960-1965
  - Virginia Science Talent Search Reports, 1966-1969
  - Virginia Science Talent Search Committee Duties, 1967-1968
  - Honorable Mentions of the Science Talent Search (filmstrip), 1956
  - Annual Science Talent Search Honor Group (filmstrip), 1963
  - Personal Data Science Service (filmstrip), 1964
  - Science Service Honors Groups and Winners (filmstrip), 1965-1966
  - Annual Science Talent Search Honors of Virginia (filmstrip), 1967
  - Annual Science Talent Search Winners of Virginia (filmstrip), 1968
  - Science Talent Search Honors (filmstrip), 1969
  - National Winners of the Science Talent Search from Virginia (filmstrip), 1969
  - Virginia Honors Group (filmstrip).
  - Three unidentified filmstrips.
  - Five filmstrips of the Personal Data Blank of the Science Talent Search.
- Box 35, W. E. Trout Papers, 1937-1978 (Box 35)
  - VAS Correspondence, 1937-1938
  - Papers from VAS meetings, 1938
  - Symposium on Agricultural Chemistry, 1938
  - Secretary of the Chemistry Section of the VAS at VPI, 1938
  - VAS Meeting, 1938
  - VAS Proceedings, 1938
  - Chemistry Section (2 folders), 1939
  - Committee on Junior Members, 1940-1942
  - Virginia Junior Academy of Science, 1940-1941, 1943-1944
  - Southern Association for the Advancement of Science, 1941-1942
  - VAS Meeting Reminiscences (1925), 1964-1973
  - Virginia Academy of Science, 1975-1977
  - VAS Meeting--Bicentennial program, 1976
  - "Physical Sciences in Virginia"--Notes (11 folders), 1976
  - "Physical Sciences in Virginia"--Rough Draft (4 folders), 1976
  - "Physical Sciences in Virginia"--Manuscript copy, 1976
  - Monograph--Notes, November 20, 1977
  - VAS Meeting, 1978
- Box 36, E. L. Wisman Papers, 1973-1974 (Box 36)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1973-1974
  - Local Arrangements--Minutes and miscellaneous, 1973-1975
  - VAS Committees, 1974
  - VAS Correspondence--Miscellaneous, 1974
  - VAS Section Activities, 1974
  - Local Arrangements Committee reports, 1974
  - Archives, 1974
  - Virginia Junior Academy of Science meeting program, 1974
  - VAS Meeting--Program Preparation, 1974
- Box 37
  - VAS 1985-1986 (Box-folder 37-1)
  - VAS 1986-1987 (Box-folder 37-2)
  - VAS 1987-1988 (Box-folder 37-3)
  - VAS 1988-1989 (Box-folder 37-4)
  - VAS 1989-1990 (Box-folder 37-5)
  - VAS 1990-1992 (Box-folder 37-6)
  - VAS 1991-1992 (Box-folder 37-7)
  - VAS 1992-1993 (Box-folder 37-8)
  - VAS 1993-1994 (Box-folder 37-9)
  - VAS 1994-1995 (Box-folder 37-10)
  - VAS Abstract Forms (Box-folder 37-11)
  - Virginia Academy-William and Mary (Box-folder 37-12)
  - VAS AGM, 1987 (Box-folder 37-13)
  - VAS AGM, 1988 (Box-folder 37-14)
  - VAS Awards Committee, 1990 (Box-folder 37-15)
  - VAS Awards Committee, 1991 (Box-folder 37-16)
  - VAS Awards Committee, 1992 (Box-folder 37-17)
  - VAS Awards Committee, 1993 (Box-folder 37-18)
  - VAS Constitution and Bylaws, Folder 1-2 (Box-folder 37-19)
  - VAS Constitution and Bylaws, Folder 2-2 (Box-folder 37-20)
  - VAS Correspondence, 1984-1985 (Box-folder 37-21)
  - VAS Creation (Box-folder 37-22)
  - VAS Directory (Box-folder 37-23)
  - VAS Evolution (Box-folder 37-24)
  - VAS Fall Council (Box-folder 37-25)
  - VAS Fellows Fund, Folder 1-2 (Box-folder 37-26)
  - VAS Fellows Fund, Folder 2-2 (Box-folder 37-27)
  - VAS Finances (Box-folder 37-28)
  - VAS Long Range Planning (Box-folder 37-29)
  - VAS March Council (Box-folder 37-30)
  - VAS Minutes, 1985-1986 Meetings (Box-folder 37-31)
  - VAS Museums (Box-folder 37-32)
  - VAS Newsletter (Box-folder 37-33)
  - VAS Proposed Publication Budget (Box-folder 37-34)
  - VAS Secretary, 1984-1985 (Box-folder 37-35)
  - VAS Treasury (Box-folder 37-36)
  - VAS Visiting Scientists (Box-folder 37-37)
  - VAS World Watch Conference, 1994 (Box-folder 37-38)
- Box 38
  - Awards at the Golden Anniversary of the VJAS (Box-folder 38-1)
  - Calls for Papers and Appeals to Membership (Box-folder 38-2)
  - "Cockroach Periplanta Americana" Susie Hohing, April 30 1974 (Box-folder 38-3)
  - Dedication of the Roscoe Durall Huges Memorial Plaque, 1989 (Box-folder 38-4)
  - Dedication Materials for the Science Museum of Virginia- Agenda, Informal Items, and Discussion Items (Box-folder 38-5)
  - "The Effects of Electric Current on the Regenerative Processes of Brown Planaria (Dugesia Dorotocaphala)" Ellen M. Clark (Box-folder 38-6)
  - "The Effects of Ultra-Violent Radiation Upon the Mutating of Sacchromyces Cerevisiae (Yeast)" Sally Ann Reed, 1973 (Box-folder 38-7)
  - "A Fifty Year History of the Virginia Junior Academy of Science" Hubert J. Davis (Box-folder 38-8)
  - "A History of the Virginia Academy of Science 1923-1945" Harry Staggers, 1996 Copy (Box-folder 38-9)
  - Laboratory Manual, Microbiology for Nurses, University of Virginia, Hospital School of Nursing, 1949-1950 (Box-folder 38-10)
  - Laboratory Directions for General Biology (Box-folder 38-11)
  - Lab Manual for General Zoology, 1948, Miller School of Biology, University of Virginia (Box-folder 38-12)
  - Martha Roane Biography (Box-folder 38-13)
  - Report to Counsel, AAAS Representative, March 1997 (Box-folder 38-14)
  - A Report to Council by Gerald R. Taylor, 1994 (Box-folder 38-15)
  - Science Museum of Virginia- Agenda, Information, and Discussion Items (Box-folder 38-16)
  - A Study of the Cyclic Behavior of the Testis of Cambarus Longulus Longulus, Vera Frances Boron, University of Virginia, 1951 (Box-folder 38-17)
  - Science Museum of Virginia Foundation- Modified Development Audit (Box-folder 38-18)
  - Science Museum of Virginia- Minutes of Joint Retreat (Box-folder 38-19)
  - Science Museum of Virginia- Report on Audit for the Year End, June 1994 (Box-folder 38-20)
  - "Scope, Sequence, and Coordination- A Historical Perspective" Pamela Turpin, Roanoke College Chemistry Department, 1997 (Box-folder 38-21)
  - Obituaries, VAS Members and Donors (Box-folder 38-22)
  - Peer Reviews of VAJAS Associate Director (Box-folder 38-23)
  - "UVA: Thomas Jefferson's Acedemical Village" Record 1979-1980 (Box-folder 38-24)
  - VAS 1982-1983, H. Bull as President Elect (Box-folder 38-25)
  - VAS 1983-1984, Correspondence from President- Elect Harold Bell (Box-folder 38-26)
  - VAS Correspondence 1989-1996 (Box-folder 38-27)
  - VAS Council Meeting, 1990 (Box-folder 38-28)
  - VAS Council Meeting Minutes, 1995 (Box-folder 38-29)
  - VAS Council Meetings, 1996 (Box-folder 38-30)
  - VAS Committee Chairpersons, 1999-200 (Box-folder 38-31)
  - VAS Fellows Newsletter, 1996 (Box-folder 38-32)
  - VAS Fundraising 1997 (Box-folder 38-33)
  - VAS George Jeffers Donation Fund Materials (Box-folder 38-34)
  - VAS Schedule of Responsibilities for the Annual Meeting, 1983-84, F. Leftwich as President-Elect (Box-folder 38-35)
  - VAS Schedule of Responsibilities for the Annual Meeting, 1984-1985, R. Gerald Class as President Elect (Box-folder 38-36)
  - VAS Schedule of Responsibilities 1999-2000 (Box-folder 38-37)
  - VAS 1983-1984, Standing Committees (Box-folder 38-38)
  - VAS Trust Funds, 1996 (Box-folder 38-39)
  - VAS Trust Fund Summary of Receipts, Disbursements, and Year-end Balances, 1998 (Box-folder 38-40)
  - VAS and VJAS Virginia Teen Branch (Box-folder 38-41)
  - VJAS 1987 Annual Meeting Materials (Box-folder 38-42)
  - VJAS August 1999 Report (Box-folder 38-43)
  - "VJAS- Its Beginning and Development from 1941-1973" (Box-folder 38-44)
  - Vera Remsburg Correspondence (Box-folder 38-45)
  - Vera Remsburg Papers, 1995-1996 (Box-folder 38-46)
  - Virginia Wildlife and Fisheries: Conservation Documents and Pamphlets (Box-folder 38-47)
  - Visiting Scientists Program (Box-folder 38-48)
- Box 39, Publications
  - An Assessment of the Programs, Staff, and Facilities of Virginia Public High School Science Departments
  - The BSCS Journal
    - Vol. 1, no. 1
    - Vol. 2, no. 2
    - May, 1969
  - The Colonnade
    - May, 1942
    - November, 1941
    - April, 1939
    - June, 1939
  - Science Museum of Virginia Annual Report
    - 1992-1993
    - 1991-1992
  - Science Museum of Virginia Base Budget Documentation, 1994-1996
  - Science Museum of Virginia Group Visit Planning Guide
    - 1992-1993
    - 1994-1995
  - The Science Museum of Virginia Newsletter
    - April, May, June, 1995
    - January, February, March, 1994
    - July, August, September, 1993
    - October, November, December, 1993
    - October, November, December, 1992
    - July, August, September, 1992
    - July, August, September, 1992
    - July, August, September 1991
  - The Virginia Academy of Science Proceedings
  - Virginia Eagles Newsletter
    - October, November, December, 1994
    - November, December 1993
  - Virginia Journal of Science
    - Vol. 19, no. 2, 4
    - Vol. 21, no. 1, 3-4
    - Vol. 22, no. 2-4
    - Vol. 23, no. 1-2, 4
    - Vol. 24, no. 4
    - Vol. 25, no. 1-2
  - Liberty Magazine, March 1942
  - A Study for the Science Museum of Virginia, Chapters 1, 2, April 1988
- Box 40, Publications
  - "The Educative Experience," John P. Wayne
  - Bulletin of the State Teachers College, Farmville Virginia
    - 1938-1939
    - 1940-1941
  - "The NSTA Story 1944/1974," Robert H. Carlton (2)
  - The Virginia Journal of Science
    - Vol. 44, no. 4
    - Vol. 45, no. 2-4
    - Vol. 46, no. 1-4
    - Vol. 47, no. 1-4
    - Vol. 48, no. 1-4
    - 1994-1995 Directory
    - 1995-1996 Directory
    - 1995-1996 Directory
    - 1997-1998 Directory
  - The Virginia Academy of Science Directory
    - 1974-1975
    - 1975-1976
    - 1976-1977
    - 1977-1978
    - 1979-1980
    - 1982-1983
    - 1983-1984
    - 1984-1985 (2)
    - 1985-1986
    - 1986-1987 (3)
    - 1987-1988 (2)
  - Virginia Academy of Science Annual Meeting Program
    - 1929
    - 1932
    - 1933
    - 1935
    - 1936
    - 1937
    - 1938
    - 1939
    - 1944
    - 1957
    - 1961
    - 1962
    - 1964
    - 1967
    - 1968
    - 1970
    - 1971
    - 1972
    - 1973
    - 1974
    - 1975
    - 1976
    - 1977
    - 1978
    - 1979
    - 1980
    - 1981
    - 1983
    - 1984
    - 1985
    - 1986
    - 1987
    - 1988
    - 1989
    - 1990
    - 1991
    - 1992
    - 1993
    - 1994
    - 1995
    - 1996
    - 1997
    - 1998
    - 1999
    - 2000
  - The Virginia Academy of Science Proceedings
    - 1931-1932
    - 1932-1933
    - 1933-1934
    - 1934-1935
    - 1935-1936
    - 1936-1937
    - 1937-1938
    - 1938-1939
    - 1942-1943
    - 1944-1945
    - 1945-1946
    - 1946-1947
    - 1947-1948
    - 1948-1949
    - 1959-1960
    - 1961-1962
  - War Department Pre-Induction Training Course Pamphlets
    - Fundamentals of Electricity
    - Fundamentals of Machines
    - Fundamentals of Radio
- Box 41, James P. O'Brien Papers
  - Complimentary Copies: VA Scientists, 1990-1991 (Box-folder 41-1)
  - News and Information Committee, 1990 (Box-folder 41-2)
  - News and Information Committee, 1991 (Box-folder 41-3)
  - Council Meeting Papers, 1992-1993 (Box-folder 41-4)
  - Schedule of Responsibilities Final, 1993-1999 (Box-folder 41-5)
  - Invitation to Exhibit, May 1993 (Box-folder 41-6)
  - VA Academy of Science 70th Annual Meeting and VA Junior Academy of Science 51st Annual Meeting, May 1992 (Box-folder 41-7)
  - President Elect/Program Chair Report, November 1992 (Box-folder 41-8)
  - VA Sci Editor Report, 1992 (Box-folder 41-9)
  - Psychology Section Report, November 1992 (Box-folder 41-10)
  - TCC/CIT [Jharrel.cit], 1992 (Box-folder 41-11)
  - VA Scis, January 1993 (Box-folder 41-12)
  - Cairns II, 1992 (Box-folder 41-13)
  - Exhibitors, September 1992 (Box-folder 41-14)
  - Talloires World Watch- Va Tech- Wallace, September 1992 (Box-folder 41-15)
  - Cook, New Editor, n.d. (Box-folder 41-16)
  - Officers Note, 1992-1993 (Box-folder 41-17)
  - 2nd Call/Section, n.d. (Box-folder 41-18)
  - VCU Biophysics Conference, 1994 (Box-folder 41-19)
  - Rivers Symposia, 1992-1993 (Box-folder 41-20)
  - New Archivist, September 1992 (Box-folder 41-21)
  - Golde-Student Awards, 1992 (Box-folder 41-22)
  - Anthropologists-Human Genome note, September 1992 (Box-folder 41-23)
  - VS, October 1992 (Box-folder 41-24)
  - VIMS (2 Articles,) n.d. (Box-folder 41-25)
  - Misc., 1992 (Box-folder 41-26)
  - SMV, 1992 (Box-folder 41-27)
  - James River Basin Sale, 1992 (Box-folder 41-28)
  - Area Events, 1992 (Box-folder 41-29)
  - Virginia Scientists, Fall 1992 (Box-folder 41-30)
  - Rabies-Carvel, 1992 (Box-folder 41-31)
  - Negus, 1992 (Box-folder 41-32)
  - Jeffers Lecture, 1993 (Box-folder 41-33)
  - Year in Review, 1992 (Box-folder 41-34)
  - Annenberg/CPB Project, 1992 (Box-folder 41-35)
  - VAS Meeting, 1992 (Box-folder 41-36)
  - VS March Issue, 1993 (Box-folder 41-37)
  - Budget/Funding of VA Sci Res/Sci Ed and Comments, 1992 (Box-folder 41-38)
  - VAS Volunteer/In-Find Service Survey, 1992 (Box-folder 41-39)
  - Correspondence of Recruitment to James P.B. O'Brien, March 1991 (Box-folder 41-40)
  - Photos (Misc), n.d. (Box-folder 41-41)
  - Newspaper Clippings and Articles, 1993 (Box-folder 41-42)
  - Photos (Labeled), n.d. (Box-folder 41-43)
  - Events, April 1993 (Box-folder 41-44)
  - Greg VA Scis, n.d. (Box-folder 41-45)
  - VA Academy of Science 71st Annual Meeting and VA Jr. Academy of Science 52nd Annual Meeting (program), 1993 (Box-folder 41-46)
  - VJAS Readers Panel Pres Thanks, 1974 (Box-folder 41-47)
  - VJAS Planning and Awards, 1991 (Box-folder 41-48)
  - VJAS Regis Packets, 1993 (Box-folder 41-49)
  - VJAS Winners Hometown Media, 1990s (Box-folder 41-50)
  - Disney's America Letters, 1994 (Box-folder 41-51)
  - VA Space Grant Consortium, 1994 (Box-folder 41-52)
  - EcoMAPS: Adam Frisch, 1994 (Box-folder 41-53)
  - Kings Dominion: Angie Sizer, 1994 (Box-folder 41-54)
  - LEGOdacta-Ron Revere, 1994 (Box-folder 41-55)
  - Richmond Med Association Auxilliary, January 1994 (Box-folder 41-56)
  - Jeffers Donors, 1993 (Box-folder 41-57)
  - Southwest VA Higher Education-Dr. Fowlkes, 1993 (Box-folder 41-58)
  - America Tobacco Company-VJAS Proceedings, January 1994 (Box-folder 41-59)
  - VASTVJAS.AD, 1993 (Box-folder 41-60)
  - Beverly Orndorff Richmond Times-Dispatch, 1994 (Box-folder 41-61)
  - Bus/Inst Members Renewal, 1993 (Box-folder 41-62)
  - VAS President's File for 1994/JMU, 1994 (Box-folder 41-63)
  - LAC 1994-JMU, 1994 (Box-folder 41-64)
  - VAS/VJAS Mtg Income/STATS ODU, 1993 (Box-folder 41-65)
  - 71st VAS Mtg Banquet invitations, 1993 (Box-folder 41-66)
  - VAS-Council Mtg 73rd Annual Mtg Presidents Luncheon, 1994 (Box-folder 41-67)
  - JMU /94 Program from Elsa, 1994 (Box-folder 41-68)
  - Elsa to Presenters, 1994 (Box-folder 41-69)
  - Elsa to Section Secretaries, 1994 (Box-folder 41-70)
  - JMU/94 Call, 1994 (Box-folder 41-71)
  - VAS Jan 94 Mailing to Members, 1994 (Box-folder 41-72)
  - 93-94 VAS Officers, 1993-1994 (Box-folder 41-73)
  - Executive Committee, 1994 (Box-folder 41-74)
  - Council Mailings, 1994 (Box-folder 41-75)
  - President-Elect, 1994 (Box-folder 41-76)
  - Secretary, 1993 (Box-folder 41-77)
  - Treasurer, 1993 (Box-folder 41-78)
  - VAS Financial Info, 1993-1994 (Box-folder 41-79)
  - Emeritus Membership, 1993 (Box-folder 41-80)
  - Ad Procedure-VAS Pubs-Exec Committee, 1993 (Box-folder 41-81)
  - RE ODU/93 Non-paying Presenters Letter 1994, 1993-1994 (Box-folder 41-82)
  - VA_CMTES DIR, 1993 (Box-folder 41-83)
  - Archives Committee, 1992-1993 (Box-folder 41-84)
  - Awards Committee, 1993 (Box-folder 41-85)
  - Constitution and Bylaws Committee, 1993 (Box-folder 41-86)
  - Finance and Endowment Committee, 1994 (Box-folder 41-87)
  - Fund Raising Committee, 1993 (Box-folder 41-88)
  - Junior Academy of Science Committee, 1994 (Box-folder 41-89)
  - Long Range Planning Committee, 1993 (Box-folder 41-90)
  - Membership Committee, 1993 (Box-folder 41-91)
  - Nominations and Elections Committee, 1993 (Box-folder 41-92)
  - Publications Committee, 1994 (Box-folder 41-93)
  - Research Committee, 1993 (Box-folder 41-94)
  - Science Advisory Committee, 1993 (Box-folder 41-95)
  - Science Education Committee, 1993 (Box-folder 41-96)
  - Trust Committee, 1993 (Box-folder 41-97)
  - VAS Futures Special Committees, 1993-1994 (Box-folder 41-98)
  - Public Affairs Committee, 1994 (Box-folder 41-99)
  - 75th Anniversary Special Committee, n.d. (Box-folder 41-100)
  - Gwaltney & Jeffress Trusts, 1993 (Box-folder 41-101)
  - AAAS (Section Y too), 1993 (Box-folder 41-102)
  - Kosztarab VNHS/VAS NH & Biodiversity, 1993 (Box-folder 41-103)
  - Biophysics Sections, 1992 (Box-folder 41-104)
  - VAS Psych Section 93, 1993 (Box-folder 41-105)
  - Dr. Bosher, 1994 (Box-folder 41-106)
  - Dr. Harvey Pres Hampton University, 1993 (Box-folder 41-107)
  - Dr. Sullivan Pres. William and Mary, 1993 (Box-folder 41-108)
  - Dean Stillman EVMS, 1994 (Box-folder 41-109)
  - Torgerson VPI & SU, 1994 (Box-folder 41-110)
  - Norfolk Southern Bob Fort, 1993 (Box-folder 41-111)
  - WGBH, 1994 (Box-folder 41-112)
  - Museum of Middle Appalachians, 1993 (Box-folder 41-113)
  - Danville Science Museum, 1994 (Box-folder 41-114)
  - Intellectual Property Section, VA State Bar Attn., 1994 (Box-folder 41-115)
  - Jim Wightman, 1994 (Box-folder 41-116)
  - Dr. Sonenshine, 1994 (Box-folder 41-117)
- Box 42, James P. O'Brien Papers
  - VAS Publications Committee (Publicity), n.d. (Box-folder 42-1)
  - KJAS Handbook/Revisions, n.d. (Box-folder 42-2)
  - VJAS Winners Hometown 92, 1992 (Box-folder 42-3)
  - Chancellor Oliver-VJAS Regionalization, 1992 (Box-folder 42-4)
  - Cottingham Press Release, 1992 (Box-folder 42-5)
  - 92 UR PI Office Bishop/Fitzgerald, 1992 (Box-folder 42-6)
  - 92 VJAS Awards Script, 1992 (Box-folder 42-7)
  - VJAS Awards Descriptions, 1992 (Box-folder 42-8)
  - Mailing List, 1992 (Box-folder 42-9)
  - Virginia Scientist Newsletter, 1991-1992 (Box-folder 42-10)
  - Virginia Sci., September 1992 (Box-folder 42-11)
  - VA Sci. Assoc. Editors, 1992 (Box-folder 42-12)
  - Geography Section-Stephen Wright, 1992 (Box-folder 42-13)
  - Don Cottingham, 1992 (Box-folder 42-14)
  - Awards, 1992 (Box-folder 42-15)
  - VAS Banquet Photos, 1992 (Box-folder 42-16)
  - VAS 1985, 1985 (Box-folder 42-17)
  - May 1993 ODU Council, 1993 (Box-folder 42-18)
  - Council, March 7, 1993 (Box-folder 42-19)
  - Council Exec Committee, November 15, 1992 (Box-folder 42-20)
  - Council Exec Committee, May 20 & 21, 1992 (Box-folder 42-21)
  - Council, March 7, 1992 (Box-folder 42-22)
  - Council, November 7, 1991 (Box-folder 42-23)
  - Council/Va Tech Meeting, May 22, 1991 (Box-folder 42-24)
  - VAS Meeting Material, 1991 (Box-folder 42-25)
  - VAS Council Meeting, November 4, 1990 (Box-folder 42-26)
  - VAS Council, May 23, 1990 (Box-folder 42-27)
  - VAS News & Info, 1991 (Box-folder 42-28)
  - New VAS Section Materials, 1990-1991 (Box-folder 42-29)
  - VAS Membership Brochure, 1985 (Box-folder 42-30)
  - Psychology Section 5191, 1991 (Box-folder 42-31)
  - VA Psych Foundations Board, 1985-1991 (Box-folder 42-32)
  - VAS Psychology Section, January 1990-November 1990 (Box-folder 42-33)
  - VAS Psychology Section, May 1988-1989 (Box-folder 42-34)
  - Virginia Scientists Next Issues, 1991 (Box-folder 42-35)
  - VA Scis. Vol I, Iss 3, March 1991 (Box-folder 42-36)
  - VA Scis Vol I, Iss 2, November 1990 (Box-folder 42-37)
  - Correspondence, 1991 (Box-folder 42-38)
  - VA Scis Vol I, Iss 1, August 1990 (Box-folder 42-39)
  - VAS Pres- PSA, 1993 (Box-folder 42-40)
  - VAS Visiting Scientist Program, 1991 (Box-folder 42-41)
  - VAS Sea;s-Transperincies, n.d. (Box-folder 42-42)
  - Dennis JMU, 1995 (Box-folder 42-43)
  - Nicely, 1995 (Box-folder 42-44)
  - Potential Members Info, 1993-1994 (Box-folder 42-45)
  - VAS Membership Material, n.d. (Box-folder 42-46)
  - Virginia Scientist Layout, n.d. (Box-folder 42-47)
  - John Cairns Publications, n.d. (Box-folder 42-48)
  - Photographs, n.d. (Box-folder 42-49)
- Box 43, James P. O'Brien Papers
  - Correspondence, 1994-1996 (Box-folder 43-1)
  - Administrative Files, 1994 (Box-folder 43-2)
  - Call for Papers, 1990 (Box-folder 43-3)
  - VAS Council, 11/5/95 (Box-folder 43-4)
  - Psychology Section Report, 11/6/94 (Box-folder 43-5)
  - VJAS, 1995-1996 (Box-folder 43-7)
  - VJAS Directorship Proposal, n.d. (Box-folder 43-8)
  - My Resol & Posit Paper, 1995 (Box-folder 43-9)
  - Long Range Planning, 1998 (Box-folder 43-10)
  - VAS Schedule of Responsibilities, 1998-1999 (Box-folder 43-11)
  - VAS EC & Council Minutes (GMU), 3/14/98 (Box-folder 43-12)
  - VAS EC & Council Minutes (GMU), 5/29/98 (Box-folder 43-13)
  - Endowed C.O. Chairs FRC, n.d. (Box-folder 43-14)
  - SCHEV Address Brochures, 1996 (Box-folder 43-15)
  - VAS, 1998 (Box-folder 43-16)
  - Report of Chanco 96 to Chanco 98, 1996-1998 (Box-folder 43-17)
  - Chanco 98 Correspondence, 1998 (Box-folder 43-18)
  - Chanco 98 Maps, 1998 (Box-folder 43-19)
  - VAS Leadership Retreat, 1998 (Box-folder 43-20)
  - Report of Chanco 96 to Chanco 98, 1996-1998 (Box-folder 43-21)
  - VAS Leadership Retreat Mailings, 1996 (Box-folder 43-22)
  - Retreat Responses & Correspondences, 1996 (Box-folder 43-23)
  - PBS/WNET, 1994 (Box-folder 43-24)
  - VJAS Board, 1994 (Box-folder 43-25)
  - Videotape/Photography Schedule, 1994 (Box-folder 43-26)
  - Final Draft The VJAS Experience, n.d. (Box-folder 43-27)
  - Polit Issue, 1995 (Box-folder 43-28)
  - VCU, 1996 (Box-folder 43-29)
  - VAS Meeting, 1996 (Box-folder 43-30)
  - Virginia Scientists, n.d. (Box-folder 43-31)
  - Senior Program, 1993 (Box-folder 43-32)
  - VAS Bills, 1994-1996 (Box-folder 43-33)
  - Postcards, Stickers, Stationary, 1992-1993 (Box-folder 43-34)
  - VS Printing, 1992-1993 (Box-folder 43-35)
  - VS Receipts, 1991-1992 (Box-folder 43-36)
  - Fact Sheets & Forms, n.d. (Box-folder 43-37)
  - Seal, 1993 (Box-folder 43-38)
  - James River Basin, 1996 (Box-folder 43-39)
  - TCC PSA & News Release Form, n.d. (Box-folder 43-40)
  - PSA, 1993 (Box-folder 43-41)
  - Council, Nov 7, 93 (Box-folder 43-42)
  - Minutes, November 7, 1993 (Box-folder 43-43)
  - Letter to MBRS, 1994 (Box-folder 43-44)